MAD
随着年岁渐长我意识到生活就是不同的视点与看法
As I get a little older, I realize life is perspective
MAD
而我的看法或许与你的不同
And my perspective may differ firom yours
MAD
我想感谢每一个同我一路走来的人
I wanna say thank you to everyone thats been down with me
MAD
我所有的粉丝所有亲爱的粉丝
A All my fans, all my beautiful fans
MAD
谢谢所有曾倾听过我的人还有我所有的同胞
MA Anyone who's ever gave me a listen, all my people
我来自苦痛的一代在那里谋杀也不足挂齿
MA B I come from a generation of pain, where murder is minor
叛逆少年和拖车房里的混混能为了一件衣服就把你砍了
Rebellious and Margielasll chip you for designer
皮带扣和街头势力当谈论到暴力时总是过分热忧
Belt buckles and clout, overzealous if prone to violence
拐错了弯不论是出于自由意志还是汽车的四轮定位错误
Make the wrong turn, be it will or the wheel alignment
汽车的残骸被烧毁你在市中心贫民区失踪
Residue burned, missed at a inner-city
简单的误解就让凶杀科警探一顿好忙
Miscommunication to keep homi' detective busy
在城市里不带保护穿行太危险
No protection is risky
麻木不仁 我肆意破坏着自己的痛苦
Desensitized, I vandalized pain
遮蔽伪装自己的感受
Covered up and camouflaged
逐渐习惯耳旁的枪林弹雨
Get used to hearin' arsenal rain
权衡利弊赌上性命然后被判刑
Analyze, risk your life, take the charge
你在监狱放风的时候那些“兄弟”就和你女朋友厮混在家这就是“文化”
MA Homies done fucked your baby mama once you hit the yard, thats culture
重罪犯监狱里禁闭接着接到某人的电话
Twenty-three hour lockdown, then somebody called
告诉你你的小侄子被人击倒就因为这“文化”
B Said your lil nephew was shot down, the cultures involved
我看过太多同胞沉迷那价值17k的货被送去戒毒所
I done seen niggas do seventeen, hit the halfway house
刚出来就被人一枪爆头只因为想买点叶子爽爽
Get out and get his brains blown out, lookin' to buy some weed
洗车场募捐已经过时了现在他的葬礼费用要跟进GoFundMe账号
MA Car'wash is played out, new GoFundMe accountsll proceed
一个崭新的受害者就能粉碎所有的幻梦还有这“文化”
MA A brand-new vietimll shatter those dreams, the culture
MAD
Marvin Gaye -I Want You 1976
(I want, I want, I want, I want)
但我想要你也渴望我
But I'want you to want me too (I want, I want, I want, I want)
我想要街头让我回去
MA I want'the hood to want me back (I want, I want, I want, I want)
我想要我的街头
MA I want the hood
看看我为你所做的全部
Look what I done for you (Look what I done for you)
Look what I done for you
MA D H
我说我做这一切都为了我的文化
I said Id do this for my culture
为了让你们看看黑哥们坐在防弹路虎上是什么样
MA To let y'all know what a nigga look like in a bulletproof Rover
在我妈沙发上放着一把.22手枪
In my mamas sofa was a doo-doo popper
一触即发再走近看看这可不是pS伪造
M Hair trigger, walk up closer, ain't no Photoshoppin
躁郁症的朋友们靠你的钱袋把你套牢
Friends bipolar, grab you by your pockets
没有歇口气的选项要一直扮演那个冒犯者
MA No option if you firoze up, always play the offense
同胞们去工作兜售工作工作迟到
MA Niggas goin' to work and sellin' work, late for work
忙到深夜 或者在缓刑期祈祷着工作
MA Workin' late, prayin' for work, but he on paperwork
这就是“文化” 指责他人推销自己
MA That's the culture, point the finger, promote ya
在偏远地区将证人保护帮派要把你暗杀
MA Remote location, witness protection, they gon' hold ya
街头真的搞砸了我你们可以怀念我
B The streets got me fucked up, yall can miss me
因为我想要为了我们代表文化
I wanna represent, for us
MAD
崭新的革命正升起并前进
MA New revolution was up and movin!
在阿根廷擦去我满是不解的泪水
MA Im in Argentina wiping my tears full of confusion
你我之间的冥河又一位兄弟被帮派行刑
MA Water in between us, another peer's been executed
历史再次重演
History repeats again
赔罪道歉接着找一个和你同样肤色的同胞再做一次
MA B Make amends, then find a nigga with the same skin to do it
MAD
但这就是“文化”啊打开手中的酒瓶
But that's the culture, crack a bottle
当你清醒的时候太难和痛苦周旋
Hard to deal with the pain when youlre sober
到了明天我们又忘了幸存者我们重蹈覆辙
MA By tomorrow, we forget the remains, we start over
这就是问题所在
A That's the problem
我们的内里被驯化能接受任何会发生的一切
Our foundation was trained to accept whatever follows
MAD
非人化麻木不仁
MA Dehumanize, insensitive
为了我们彼此好好想想我们是怎样生活的
Scrutinize the way we live for you and I
敌人啊与我握手保证我还会与你再见面
MA Enemies shook my hand, I can promise Ill meet you
就那片土地上在那里不平等就是你的平等
In the land where no equal is your equal
别说我没告诉过你
Never say I ain't told ya, nah
就那片土地上在那里我们伤害别人再伤害更多的人
B In the land where hurt people hurt more people
还他妈叫它“文化”
MA Fuck callin' it culture
MAD
（我想我想我想
(I want, I want, I want, I want)
但我想要你也渴望我
But I'want you to want me too (I want, I want, I want, I want)
MAD
我想要街头让我回去
MA I want'the hood to want me back (I want, I want, I want, I want)
我想要我的街头
MA I want the hood
看看我为你所做的全部
MA Look what I done for you (Look what I done for you)
MAD
看看我为你所做的全部
MA Look what I done for you
MAD
把鼓点停下来
Take the drums out
MAD
当努力的成果回报庆祝这全新的生活
MA Celebrate new life when it come back around
人生的目的是专注学习当下就好
MA The purpose is in the lessons we learnin' now
为了其他的所有牺牲个人私利
MA Saerifice personal gain over everything
就为了看到下一代比我们成长的环境更好
MA Just to see the next generation better than ours
我并不完美我所栖的皮肤经历磨难
MA I wasn't perfect, the skin I was in had truly suffered
诱惑与耐心这副身躯受到一切的滋养
Temptation and patience, everything that the body nurtures
我感受善我感受恶我感受忧虑
I Telt the good, I felt the bad, and I felt the worry
但最终我的创造力总是如此急切
But all-in-all, my productivity had stayed urging
直面恐惧一直知道总有天我会走到这里
Face your fears, always knew that I would make it here
在这里我的力量无限放大不屈不挠
Where the energy is magnified and persevered
我的意识与祂同步水晶般清晰
MA Consciousness is synchronized and crystal-clear
赞美这份愉悦
MA Buphoria is glorified and made His
上帝之光照耀在我的生活与成就之上
MA Reflectin' on my life and what I done
辛苦的回报设立自己的准则因为爱而改变
MA Paid dues, made rules, change outta love
这同样的观点让学校改变了教授的课程
M B Them same views made schools change currieulums
但却没能避免我凝视着那杆枪
B But didn't change me starin' down the barrel of that gun
我是否应悔恨还未见过自己的全部潜力是什么模样
MA B Should I feel resentful I didn't see my full potential?
我是否应后悔我选择了善的方向
Should I feel regret about the good that I was into?
天行有常这一切并非巧合
MA Everything is everything, this ain't coincidental
因为我那天一醒就想向你吐露更多心声
M I woke up that morning with more heart to give you
我在麦克风前倾吐心血感受到自己的实在
MA As I bleed through the speakers, feel my presence
我的兄弟啊我的孩子们啊我正身处天堂
To my mother, to my sis, Im in Heaven
我的母亲啊我的姐妹啊我正身处天堂
我的父亲啊我的妻子啊我说真的这儿就是天堂
MA To my father, to my wife, I am serious,this is Heaven
我的朋友们啊请保证你们继续祈祷
To my firiends, make sure you countin' them blessings
我的粉丝们请保证你们继续投资
To my fans, make sure you make them investments
而对那个将我死亡提前的杀手
MA And to the killer that sped up my demise
MAD
我原谅你我知道你的灵魂也在质疑
I forgive you, just know your souls in question
在你紧握扳机的时候我在你的瞳孔里看到了痛苦
I seen the pain in your pupil when that trigger had sgueezed
尽管你对我如此丑恶我也一并释然
MA B And though you did me gruesome, I was surely relieved
尽管我已完成自己的使命尽管我未准备好离去
MA I completed my mission, wasn't ready to leave
但我的时日已圆满造物主也会欣喜
MA But fulfilled my days, my Creator was pleased
我不会强调我将怎么继续爱你们
M I can't stress how I love yall
我不需要用肉体凡胎拥抱你们
B I don't need to be in flesh just to hug yall
我的记忆因你们永远流传
I The memories recollect just because y'all
请用尊重将我悼念
A Celebrate me with respect
我们想要维护的团结高于所有
The unity we protect is above all
Sam 我的哥哥我会庇佑着你
And Sam, Il be watchin' over you
请保证我的孩子观看我所有的采访
Make sure my kids watch all my interviews
请保证你活在我们一起创造的梦想
MA Make sure you live all the dreams we produce
让你脑中的天资永远在活动中
Keep that genius in your brain on the move
我的社区啊请让善继续发扬
MA And to my neighborhood, let the good prevail
保证那些孩子们长大领我们走出监牢
MA Make sure them babies and them lead us outta jail
在水深火热之际也要始终寻找救赎
MA Look for salvation when troubles get real
因为在你帮助自己之前你无法帮助整个世界
MA 'Cause you can't help the world until you help yourself
而在被杀的那天我也无法责怪我的街头
MA And I can't blame the hood the day that I was killed
你们必须看到这一切这是感受我心的唯一方法
Yall had to see it, thats the only way to feel
尽管我的肉体无法收获这一切善果
MA And though my physical won't reap the benefits
这积极的力量会坚持散发直到永久
MA The energy that carry on emits still
我想要你也知道
MA I want you
MAD